A Finding Aid to the Francis Patrick Garvan Papers, 1867, 1912-1953, in the Archives of American Art AAA.garvfran
Archives of American Art
Francis Patrick Garvan papers
1912-1953
1867
AAA.garvfran
Archives of American Art
44.9 Linear feet
The papers of art collector Francis Patrick Garvan measure 44.9 linear feet and date from 1912 to 1953, with one document from 1867. The papers provide extensive documentation on the Garvan collection which included rare books, ceramics, glass, paintings, prints, and furniture. The majority of the collection consists of inventory records that give descriptive information regarding each piece in the collection; in many cases the files also include a photograph of the object. Also found are correspondence and subject files; auction records for sales at the American Art Association, Parke-Bernet Galleries, and Plaza Art Galleries; loan records; estate records; and a small amount of printed material, writings, and photographs. Approximately half of the Garvan papers were created posthumously by Mabel Brady Garvan and the managers of Garvan's estate.
Garvan, Francis Patrick, 1875-1937
Garvan, Mabel Brady
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 8 series.
Series 1: Correspondence and Subject Files, 1912-1942, 1953 (11.5 linear feet; Boxes 1-12, 46)
Series 2: Auction Records, circa 1930s-1949 (1.75 linear feet; Boxes 12-13)
Series 3: Loan Records, 1919-1948 (3.0 linear feet; Boxes 14-16, 46)
Series 4: Estate Records, 1929-1951 (0.75 linear feet; Box 17, 45)
Series 5: Inventory, 1928-1949 (26.0 linear feet; Boxes 17-43)
Series 6: Printed Materials, 1867, 1926-1949 (1.0 linear foot; Boxes 43-44, 46)
Series 7: Writings, 1930s (0.3 linear feet; Box 44)
Series 8: Photographic Materials, 1930s-1940s (0.8 linear feet; Boxes 44-45, 47)
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Donated 1981 by Anthony N. B. Garvan and Phil Hoyt for the estate of Mabel Brady Garvan.
Biographical/Historical note
Francis Patrick Garvan (1875-1937) and his wife Mabel Brady Garvan were art collectors in the 1920s and 1930s, specializing in decorative arts and furniture. Professionally, Garvan was a lawyer who spent the majority of his career serving as President of the Chemical Foundation, to which he was appointed by President Woodrow Wilson. He maintained relationships with many prominent museums and galleries including the American Art Association, the Anderson Galleries, the Brooklyn Museum, the Metropolitan Museum of Art, and the Whitney Museum of American Art. Over the course of his life, Garvan had amassed a collection of thousands of decorative and fine art objects. During his final years, Garvan arranged for the majority of his art collection to be donated to Yale University, his alma mater.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of art collector Francis Patrick Garvan measure 44.9 linear feet and date from 1912 to 1953, with one document from 1867. The papers provide extensive documentation on the Garvan collection which included rare books, ceramics, glass, paintings, prints, and furniture. The majority of the collection consists of inventory records that give descriptive information regarding each piece in the collection; in many cases the files also include a photograph of the object. Also found are correspondence and subject files; auction records for sales at the American Art Association, Parke-Bernet Galleries, and Plaza Art Galleries; loan records; estate records; and a small amount of printed material, writings, and photographs. Approximately half of the Garvan papers were created posthumously by Mabel Brady Garvan and the managers of Garvan's estate.
Notable correspondence is with antique, art and rare book dealers, museums, curators, conservators, Garvan's employees, George Parmly Day, Andrew Keough, and John Marshall Phillips of Yale University regarding the 1930 gift of the [Mabel Brady] Garvan Collection to Yale, as well as the American Art Association, Anderson Galleries, Inc., Francis Bigelow, Robert Ensko, Richard T. Haines Halsey, E. Alfred Jones, Fiske Kimball, William Macbeth, Inc., Wallace Nutting, Richard W. Symonds, and others.
American Art Association.; Bigelow, Francis Hill, 1859-1933; Day, George Parmly, 1876-1959; Ensko, Robert; Garvan Collection. (Yale University); Halsey, R. T. Haines, (Richard Townley Haines), 1865-1942; Jones, E. Alfred, (Edward Alfred), 1872-1943; Keough, Andrew, 1869-1953; Kimball, Fiske, 1888-1955; Macbeth Gallery; Nutting, Wallace, 1861-1941; O'Reilly's Plaza Art Galleries.; Parke-Bernet Galleries.; Phillips, John Marshall, 1905-1953; Yale University. -- Art collections; Art--Collectors and collecting; Decorative arts; Decorative arts--Collectors and collecting--New York (State)--New York; Photographs
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1912-1942; 1953; Series 1; 11.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-12, 46
  Scope and Contents note
  Found here is correspondence, object inquiries, and salse transactions with museums, curators, conservators, and other art dealers. Also included is correspondence with private individuals looking to buy decorative objects or furniture from Francis Garvan. A significant portion of the correspondence in this series regards the 1930 gift made to Yale University which included the majority of his art collection.
  - Ackerman & Sons Inc., Arthur, 1916-1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Addicks, John H., 1914-1925 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alexander & Garrett, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Aliance Realty Co., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Allison, John Wesley, 1929-1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Allyn, Elizabeth, 1934-1936 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Art Association, 1914-1937 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - American Art Association-Bills, 1913-1938 (Box 1, Folder 9-14)
  - American Art Association-Girl Scout Exhibition, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - American Art Association-Anderson Galleries, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
  - American Art Association-Objects Recieved, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 18-22)
  - American Anderson News, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - American Federation of Arts, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Amor, Albert, 1937; 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Anderson Auction, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Anderson David, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Anderson Galleries, 1920s-1930s (Box 1, Folder 28-30)
  - Anderson Galleries- Bills, 1918-1920 (Box 1, Folder 31-33)
  - Andrews, Mary, 1935-1937 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Angell, Charles, 1930-1932 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Annapolis Antiques Shop, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Antiques (magazine), 1924-1931 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Antiques Bulletin Publishing Co., 1930 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Antique Collector's League of America, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - A, Miscellaneous, 1930-1937 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Bacon, E.W., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Bailey, Harold C., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Baliozian & Bros, 1914-1933 (Box 1, Folder 43-45)
  - Barmore, Charles, 1919-1932 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Barrett, Louise, 1928-1938 (Box 1, Folder 47-50)
  - B. T. Batsford Ltd., 1929-1939 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Beard, J. K., 1928-1937 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Beard, Mabel Woolcott, 1932-1940 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Bernard, Theodore Otis, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Beutell & Sons (Henry), 1918 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Bickerton, Spencer, circa 1930s (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Bigton, Francis P., 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Bland, Harry M., 1937; 1932 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Borgioanni, Umberto, 1930-1937 (Box 1, Folder 59-61)
  - Boulton & Paul Ltd., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Brackett, Hosford, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bradley, Otis T., 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Brand-Chilton, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Brantley, Jack, 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Brinton, Francis P., 1928-1935 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Brix, Maurice, 1930-1936 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Brooks Reed Galleries, 1930-1936 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Buckley, Julian, 1932-1934 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Burnham, R. W., 1923-1932 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bury, Edmond, 1930-1937 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bush, Frederick, 1929-1930 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Busse, George, 1914-1924 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Button, H. V., 1931-1933 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - B, Miscellaneous, circa 1930s (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
  - Caldwell & Co. (J.E.), 1917-1928 (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
  - Carl Company, 1933-1936 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Carroll, Annie, 1932-1937 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Carroll, Charles, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Chambers, Eunice, 1937-1940 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Champion & Wilton, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Chapman, Henry, 1921-1934 (Box 2, Folder 23-31)
  - Charles Antiques, 1915-1918 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Charles Scribner's Sons, 1914-1937 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Childhood Inc., 1928 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Choineieres, Edmond T., 1934 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Christie, Manson & Woods, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 36-38)
  - Churchill, Arthur, 1918-1919 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - The Clapp & Graham Co. inc., 1917-1937 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Clark, Arthur W., 1915-1928 (Box 2, Folder 41-60)
  - Clark, Hermann F., 1931-1933 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Clark, Marion, 1930-1938 (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
  - Cohen & Ponell Inc., 1936-1939 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Collamore & Co. Ltd., 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Collings & Collings, 1916-1919 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Comyn & Sons, William, 1928-1933 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Cooke, Levi, 1925-1930 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Cookman, Rodney, 1932-1933 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Cooper, W. F., 1924-1928 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Crichton Bros., 1916-1933 (Box 3, Folder 14-20)
  - Crichton & Co. Ltd, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 21-23)
    Oversized material housed in box 46.
  - Curtis, Leah, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Cutten, George B., 1933-1941 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - C, Miscellaneous, 1921-1939 (Box 3, Folder 26-27)
  - Davis, Cecil, 1928-1935 (Box 3, Folder 28-29)
  - Davis, Richard Harding, 1917-1918 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Dawson Antiques, 1918-1920 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Day & Meyer, 1914-1930 (Box 3, Folder 32-33)
  - DeSherbinin, Michael, 1933-1937 (Box 3, Folder 34-35)
  - Donat, Winfield Jr., 1930-1932 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Donleavy, S. J., circa 1929 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Drake, James, 1914-1934 (Box 3, Folder 38-41)
  - Dreyfous, E., 1921 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - du Pont, Henry F., 1930-1940 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - du Pont de Nemours & Co., 1932 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Durlacher Bros., 1921-1922 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Dutton, E. P., 1915-1930 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Duveen, Albert, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - D, Miscellaneous, 1919-1937 (Box 3, Folder 48-49)
  - East Providence Church, 1931-1936 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Ehrich Galleries, 1927-1930 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Ehrich-Newttouse, 1934-1936 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Elder Coin & Curio Corporation, 1935-1937 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Elsberg, H. A., 1931-1932 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - English Furniture, 1933-1935 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Engravings, 1933-1935 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Ensko, Robert, 1934-1937 (Box 3, Folder 57-58)
  - Evan-Thomas Ltd. (Owen), 1929-1933 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Everett, W. C., 1930 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - E, Miscellaneous, 1932-1937 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Farr, Willoughby, 1931-1932 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Fergus, Amy, 1933-1935 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Fisher, Samuel, 1930-1931 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Frech, Hollis, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Fridensberg, Robert, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Friedman, Morris, 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - F, Miscellaneous, 1930-1942 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Gannon, Thomas J., 1929 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Garvan, (Mrs.) Peter Dunne, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Gautier, Louis, 1928-1930 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Gebelein, George C., 1936 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Gerte, Joseph, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Gilchrist & Co., Robert, 1920-1921 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Gill & Reigale, 1916-1921 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Gilman Collamore & Co. Inc., 1935; 1920-1927 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Ginsberg & Levy, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Goldsmith & Silversmiths Co. Ltd., 1928-1930 (Box 4, Folder 10-11)
  - Goodspeed's Bookstore, 1930-1937 (Box 4, Folder 12-18)
  - Griffith, C. H. E., 1916-1920 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Griffiths. Percival, 1928-1930 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Gumps, S. G., 1920-1937 (Box 4, Folder 21-23)
  - G, Miscellaneous, 1928-1940 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Hall, Mattie, 1930-1931 (Box 4, Folder 25-26)
  - Halsey, R. T. H., 1927-1937 (Box 4, Folder 27-35)
  - Harman & Lambert, 1928-1931 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Harper, F. C., 1922-1925 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Harris & Sons, 1927-1930 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Harris & Sinclair, 1928-1931 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - The Hayden Co., 1913-1921 (Box 4, Folder 40-41)
  - Hellier, Walter H., 1939-1941 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Henkels, Stan V., 1917-1924 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Higgs, Jackson, 1923-1936 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Higgins, John W., 1936 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Historical Societies of New York, 1920s-1930s (Box 4, Folder 46-49)
  - Hodges, Fidges, & Co. Ltd., 1929-1933 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Hidden, Agnes J., circa 1930s (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Hood, Jennings, 1930-1932 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Hooper, Roger, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Hopkins, Frederick, 1918-1922 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Hosletter, (Mrs.) Albert K., 1936 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Howard & Co., 1917-1929 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Howell, Adelaide, 1933-1940 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Howell, Katie, 1937-1941 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Hughes Bolckow Shipbreaking Co., 1927 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Hurry, Renwick C., 1920-1930 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - H, Miscellaneous, 1922-1937 (Box 4, Folder 61-62)
  - International Studios, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Ives, C. W., 1933 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - I, Miscellaneous, 1934-1937 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Jackson, William H., 1916-1927 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Jefferies, William A., 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Jensen, George, 1927-1935 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Jones, E. Alfred, 1926-1931 (Box 5, Folder 1-7)
  - Jordan, Madeline, 1919-1937 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - J, Miscellaneous, 1925-1937 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Kelekian, Dikran G., 1916-1924 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Keller, Ferdinand, 1916-1918 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Kelleher, William H., 1933-1937 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Kent Gallery, 1928-1930 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Kennedy & Co., 1920-1937 (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
  - Kindig Jr., Joe, 1932-1936 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - King, Harold, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Knipp, John C., 1918-1919 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Knittle, Rhea & Earl, 1927-1937 (Box 5, Folder 19-21)
  - Knoedler & Co., 1914-1937 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - K, Miscellaneous, 1916-1937 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Lai-yum & Co., 1917-1919 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Lawton, Herber, 1932-1937 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - John Levy Galleries, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Library of Congress, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 27-28)
  - Lindberg, Karl, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - The Little Gallery, 1916-1937 (Box 5, Folder 30-31)
  - Lobmeyer's Neffe, J. & L., 1929-1931 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Lorring, Wiliam P., 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Low, Grace B., 1931-1936 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Lusty, A. L., 1933-1934 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Lynn, 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Lynn, Charles W., 1914-1929 (Box 5, Folder 37-44)
  - L, Miscellaneous, 1929-1937 (Box 5, Folder 45-46)
  - Maag, Edward, 1930-1932 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Macbeth, William, 1916-1942 (Box 5, Folder 48-56)
  - Macbeth Galleries, 1916-1942 (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
  - MacCarthy, Frank, 1925-1930 (Box 6, Folder 4-10)
  - McKarin's Antiques, 1933-1936 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Mc, Miscellaneous, 1931-1941 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Maggs Bros., 1930-1932 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Mallet & Sons, 1928-1931 (Box 6, Folder 14-23)
  - Middlekoop, Frans, 1917-1929 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Manhattan Storage & Warehouse Co., 1916-1929 (Box 6, Folder 25-28)
  - Manufacturer's Trust Co., 1935-1937 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Margolies, Herman, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Margolis, Jacob, 1919-1927 (Box 6, Folder 31-42)
  - Margolis, Nathan, 1931-1933; 1924 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Market for Exchange, 1932-1937 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Marshall, Lois A., 1934 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Mason, Williams & French, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Merrall, Elinor, 1930-1931 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Messervy, E. L., 1933 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Metropolitian Museum of Art, 1917-1935 (Box 7, Folder 1-6)
  - Mexican Glass, circa 1930s (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Michaelsen Gallery, 1931-1937 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Milford Antique Shop, 1932-1934 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Millbrook Antique Shop, 1930-1935 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Millbrooke School for Boys, 1935-1937 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Minneapolis Institute of Arts, 1932-1933 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Miss Peacock's Antique Shop, 1916-1917 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Morris, George Ford, 1922-1933 (Box 7, Folder 14-16)
  - Morson, Charles R., 1916-1931 (Box 7, Folder 17-18)
  - Mass, Leonard H., 1936-1937 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Mumford, John and Kimberly, 1913-1917 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Myers, Florence, 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - M, Miscellaneous, 1930-1938 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Nagy, Stephen K., 1932-1937 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Nassau Massey, 1929-1933 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - National Galleries Inc., 1931-1933 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - National Studios Inc., 1931-1932 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Newhouse Galleries, 1934-1938 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Nutting, Wallace, 1917-1930 (Box 7, Folder 28-29)
  - N, Miscellaneous, 1930-1942 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Old Furniture Ltd., 1928-1931 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Old New York Plates, circa 1930s (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Old Print Shop Inc., 1932-1935 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - O, Miscellaneous, 1932-1937 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Papp, Florian, 1925-1929 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Parke-Bernet Galleries, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Parker, W. L., 1928-1930 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Partridge & Digtton, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Partridge & Sons, 1916-1935 (Box 7, Folder 38-41)
  - Pauley, Rudolph P., 1932 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Pennock, Mary, 1935-1937 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Pennypacker, A. J., 1936 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Pennypacker, Charles, 1934 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Peters, Fred J., 1931-1932 (Box 7, Folder 46-47)
  - Philadelphia Antique Co., 1934-1936 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1919-1935 (Box 7, Folder 49-56)
    Includes letter from Fiske Kimball.
  - Phillips Academy, 1929-1937 (Box 7, Folder 57-58)
  - Platt, P. G., 1932-1935 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Plumber & Co., William H., 1923-1931 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Presgraves, A. W., 1930 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - P, Miscellaneous, 1933-1941 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - The Quarters Antiques, 1928-1933 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Railway and Freight, 1937-1938 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Rains Auction Rooms, 1932-1937 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Raymond, Wayte, 1931-1933 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Reeves, Martha de Haas, 1932-1934 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Rice, William Gorham, 1931-1933 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Richmond Antiques, 1916-1936 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Robinson, James, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Rugs, 1912-1916 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Rogers Group, 1932-1933 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - R, Miscellaneous, 1931-1941 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Sabin, Frank, 1932-1935 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Sacks, Isreal, 1919-1933 (Box 8, Folder 8-10)
  - St. John, Eleanor T., 1935-1937 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Sattig, Gustave R., 1931-1932 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Sewitzy, William, 1932-1940 (Box 8, Folder 13-14)
  - Schmitt Brothers, 1916-1923 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Schulte's Bookstore Inc., undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Scott & Fowles, 1917-1935 (Box 8, Folder 17-19)
  - Sloan, W. J., 1916-1936 (Box 8, Folder 20-22)
  - Skinner's Bookstore, 1915-1917 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Secord, William R., 1931-1932 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Shea, M.A., 1932 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Shreve, Crump & Low Co., 1923-1924 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Smith, Eddy N., 1919-1920 (Box 8, Folder 27-28)
  - Smith, George D., 1917-1921 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Smith, Harry Winchester, 1915-1928 (Box 8, Folder 30-34)
  - Smith & Watson, 1915-1918 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Soane & Smith Ltd., 1916-1920 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Southard, C. H., circa 1927 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Spink & Sons Ltd., 1928-1931 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Spoons, undated (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Staal & Sons, 1924 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Stoner & Evans, 1923-1941 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Stark, Leon, 1936 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Stratford-Upon-the-Potamic, 1930-1936 (Box 8, Folder 43-49)
  - Sussell, Arthur J., 1932-1936 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Sweet, Forest H., 1933-1936 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Symans, Henry, 1915-1916 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Symonds, Robert W., 1928-1935 (Box 9, Folder 1-32)
    Oversized material is housed in box 46.
  - Symonds, Robert W. -From Notebook, 1928-1929 (Box 9, Folder 33-34)
  - S, Miscellaneous, 1928-1941 (Box 9, Folder 35-36)
  - Taylor, Henry H., 1926-1933 (Box 10, Folder 1-15)
  - Taylor, Mary D, 1930-1937 (Box 10, Folder 16-17)
  - Thomas Bradbury & Sons, 1929-1930 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Thompson, Elizabeth, 1930-1931 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Thompson, George, 1931-1932 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Thorpe, Russell W., 1921-1937 (Box 10, Folder 21-33)
  - Tiffany Studios, 1915-1917 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Tiffany & Co., 1919-1938 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Tovell, G. Walter, 1930-1934 (Box 10, Folder 36-37)
  - Traver Company, 1916-1924 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - T, Miscellaneous, 1922-1940 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - University Book Service, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - U, Miscellaneous, 1931-1940 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Valentine & Co. (H. C.), 1927-1932 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Van Houghton, C. M., 1928-1929 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Van Rensselaer, Stephan, 1921-1927 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Vernay, Arthur, 1913-1939 (Box 10, Folder 45-51)
  - Voorhees, Paul, 1931-1932 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Volpi, Elia, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - V, Miscellaneous, 1932-1935 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Waite, Hamet, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Wallace, James C., 1928 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Wallpaper, circa 1941 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Wanamaker, John, 1917-1923 (Box 11, Folder 7-8)
  - Waterman, Grace, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Wellans, Adrian F., 1931 (Box 11, Folder 10-11)
  - Weis, Gabriel, 1915-1931 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Wells & Co., John, 1915-1918 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Whiteley's, 1928-1935 (Box 11, Folder 14-15)
  - Whitlock's Inc., 1932-1938 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Whitney, Edward S., 1935 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Whitemore, J. P., 1931-1932 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Wilson, Walter H., 1929-1935 (Box 11, Folder 19-21)
  - Wilderness Antique Shops, 1933-1938 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Williams, Max, 1916-1921 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Wine, Lewis, 1933-1934 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Winslow, Arthur, 1932-1934 (Box 11, Folder 25-26)
  - Woodill, John R., 1933-1935 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - W, Miscellaneous, 1923-1937 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Yamanaka & Co., 1915-1928 (Box 11, Folder 29-30)
  - Yale-Pledges and Contributions, 1914-1925 (Box 11, Folder 31-36)
  - Yale-via George P. Day, 1915-1937 (Box 11, Folder 37-41)
  - Yale-via J. M. Phillips, 1930-1942 (Box 11, Folder 42-55)
  - Yale-Gifts, 1929-1935 (Box 12, Folder 1-4)
  - Yale-re: Marian Clark, 1928-1931 (Box 12, Folder 5-7)
  - Yale-Miscellaneous, 1918-1937 (Box 12, Folder 8-11)
  - Young, J., circa 1937 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Y-Z Miscellaneous, 1932-1937 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Oversized Critchton & Co. Inc., from Box 3, Folders 21-23, 1929 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Halsey, R. T. H., from Box 4, Folders 27-35, 1927-1937 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Phillips Academy, from Box 7, Folders 75-58, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Oversized Symonds, Robert W., from Box 9, Folders 1-32, 1928-1935 (Box 46, Folder 4)
- Auction Records, circa 1930-1949; Series 2; 1.75 Linear feet Box 12-13
  Auction records include sales records, lists, and catalogues for auctions in which much of Garvan's collection was sold during the 1930s and 1940s. The auctions were held at the American Art Association, the Parke-Bernet Galleries, and the Plaza Art Galleries.
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged as 3 subseries.